Kapil Wankhede

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kapilwankhede/

Github: https://github.com/kwankhede

www.nalanda-academy.com

Email: kapilwankhede 22@gmail.com

Mobile: +91-9987880240

Organizations: www.sanghamitra.com

www.sanghamitra.store

PROFILE

Business and social entrepreneur with six years of experience in strategic planning, public relations, organization-management, business growth, mentorship, and shared success. Currently managing a business incubator and actively contributing to the development of entrepreneurship within the community. Previously worked on financial model risk management and higher education. Strong technical and problem solving background, with degrees in data science, finance and engineering.

EDUCATION

• Udacity
Nanodegree in Data Science

Illinois Institute of Technology

• MS in Finance

Dr. B. A. Tech. University, Lonere

B. Tech in Petrochemical Engineering

Certificate

Jan 2020 - May 2020

Chicago, USA

Aug 2015 - May 2017

Raigad, India

Aug 2008 - May 2012

EXPERIENCE

Sanghamitra Business Incubator

Co-Founder and Chief Operations Officer

Wardha, India Jan 2019 - Current

- Founded an incubator focused on the finding, establishing and nurturing socially conscious businesses. Responsible for identifying, launching, operating, and scaling operations.
- Led overall operations management in product design, market research, vendor sourcing, supply chain management, quality control, sales and marketing, order fulfillment logistics, finance, and store operations, ensuring the incubator's vision is being realized.
- Led through major challenges of COVID pandemic to launch several business lines and products [www.sanghamitra.com], e-commerce website [www.sanghamitra.store] and expansion to multiple locations. [partnerships: digital nalanda]
- Hired and trained new employees, creating a working environment for informed risk-taking and rapid skill-building through real-world engagements, multidimensional exploration, trial and error experimentation, and data driven decision making.
- Established engineering lab and library, organized education and healthcare awareness workshops in the community.

Nalanda Academy

Co-Founder and Educator

Wardha, India Jul 2013 - Dec 2019

- Provided executive leadership to create a discrimination-free space and educational training for marginalized students from 15 states of India, resulting in the successful enrollment of over 800 students in leading universities in India and abroad.
- Led strategic planning, fundraising, and public relations efforts to support the growth and development of the Academy.
- Initiated 14 Abhiyan Libraries in India and managed community mobilization and operation of these libraries.

- Created and taught Mathematics, Science, Economics, Logical Reasoning and Critical Thinking syllabi.
- Oversaw Nalanda Abhiyan Labs to introduce marginalized students to the latest technologies and promote awareness of these advances.
- Assisted in launching an online learning platform currently used by 12,000 students: www.digitalnalanda.com.

Mitsubishi UFJ Financial Group Union Bank

NYC,USA

Quantitative Financial Analyst

Jun 2017-Sep 2018

- Conducted full model validation, including conceptual soundness, data analysis, computer-based implementation, regulatory and governance, and documentation, of a regulatory model that calculates counter-party credit risk.
- Handled database of the bank's 900 models and non-models for tracking their status and outstanding issues and regularly notified team members.
- Performed independent validation of Economic Capital VaR model and scorecard-based credit risk rating model, including statistical testing to validate the accuracy of model output and assigned ratings.
- Validated various market and credit risk models, including IRS, CDS, and swap pricing models using Bloomberg as a benchmark.

ACADEMIC AND SELF-DIRECTED PROJECTS

- Disaster response webapp: Developed a web application that allows emergency workers to input a new message and receive classification results in various categories using machine learning models to take actions. [GitHub]
- Diabetic Prediction model: Developed a machine learning model to predict if a person is diabetic or not, based on attributes of Pima-Indians diabetes data from UCI repository.[GitHub]
- A Financial derivative: Designed a structure note called commodity-linked note and used MATLAB to calculate its fair value, used variance reduction technique to improve results of Monte Carlo simulation. [Code] [Report]

SCHOLARSHIPS

- Recipient of National Overseas Scholarship by government of India for a foreign education.
- Next Generation Tech Booster Challenge: Front End Developer by UDACITY.

SKILLS SUMMARY

- Programming Languages: Python, R, JavaScript, VBA, MATLAB
- Frameworks: ReactJS, ExpressJS, Machine Learning
- Tools: Git, SQL, MS Office, Anaconda-navigator, Microsoft Power BI, Bloomberg, Workbench